hello and welcome to our bi-weekly live
board meeting where we are discussing
the Mehta project how can we create
tools that help all of our projects get
out into the world and how do we move
that forward especially we all have our
own projects that we're all so
passionate about so welcome to number I
hope you see the one I think it's number
ten might be 11 number 10 or meeting
number 10 oh I see yes
which is really not just like the board
me number 10 on this channel then we
have the ones previously but so we don't
have an agenda set for today right no
not specifically no I think anyone put
anything on it we don't even have the
date that's that's how we're doing you
know I think one important thing to talk
about it's kind of an offshoot of you
know that one of the more exciting
things that happen in the game bSpace
recently was though you know
conversation around the person being
racist and us not really having any
rules in place too and then trying to
react it you to that I think trying like
at some point we have to set some sort
of centered of rules is well I agree
with the outcome the fact that we didn't
have any rules at the time that the
person violet liked that part kind of
bothered me I would have rather
institute rules first and then said hey
from now on yes just so that we can do
that in other projects as well because
otherwise I think it ends up being sort
of a knee-jerk reaction or meeting i'm
mateus yeah I think that could be a
topic I guess that would be more for
together you know what are similar
policies who want in together tax slash
writing be projects the other thing is I
think it'd be good just open up and say
what are we feeling I mean we've been
kind of focusing on our projects and our
I don't think we've had the meta
discussion in a while of just
brainstorming of what do we need as
groups to come together and support each
other or is it just continually having
these meetings
I guess we could also talk over anything
that anyone posted in the Thursday
update of things they could use help
with so yeah all that I guess any other
topics people want to use this time for
I think that's a good don't wanna take
around and kind of say what the meta I
don't even know because I don't even
know what we can do like what is the
matter project the moment I'm so focused
on the other one but I'm enjoying that
it exists that it's like in the
periphery that it there it's there and
then as people are like hey I have any
world saving idea like hmm
you're the first well what do you
suggest cuz you're the absolute first
person especially the game be space um
yeah like right now I'm just focusing on
the process I'm probably saying like how
do we bring 10,000 people together and
then and then instead of pre creating
the tools how do we actually create them
so the people or the driving force
behind what tools are created and it's a
really weird position to be in because
it's all chicken and egg and all like
right we're just gonna figure out the
chaos together and own that chaos as we
go through it and so I yeah I think that
when people have a better idea of what
the meta project looks like at the
moment for them yes I think yeah we just
go round of what and see what each of us
would like out of the meta project I
also feel like before maybe we do that
Billy do want to introduce yourself
weren't really and I always an awkward
of like wait we my name is Billy
ah yeah I mean I've lately been just
trying to think about how communities
talk together about about things when
they have different people into trying
to learn more about stuff in and watch
people look trying to do it trying to
look at certain integral techniques and
hope Trotman and in terms of projects I
want to in the future figure out how to
do both leadership of communities of
figuring out to resolve disputes and
maintain everyone wanting to talk to
each other and staying on on good topics
of discussion as well as um just how to
set up conversations between people and
figure out who is a good person based on
what knowledge and experiences they have
to be to be part of the conversation and
how much you value their experiences
determining how much effort you're gonna
put into accommodating their needs maybe
they get frustrated easily when certain
things are talked about so trying to
avoid talking about those things or
something because of how valuable their
understanding might be those are just on
my mind that kind of
trying to find the intersection of like
that what they appear to value and their
skillset sort of see where they fit in
the conversation yeah just I've been
thinking about what a lot of people have
been saying about communities being like
too white and mail and stuff or whatever
like people I've been trying to learn
about trauma about how trauma works in
the brain about what kind of experiences
cause trauma and how it becomes
triggered and I mean I've I've I've been
like kicked out of group chats and stuff
for accidentally stumbling onto things
that that uh upset people and not like
figuring out how to apologize properly
or something I guess and so I've kind of
been trying to think about how to get a
better understanding of of how to avoid
avoid that this this case of it's a
failure case I guess of trying to have
conversations about things and just in
general looking at different types of
failure cases of the attempt to create
community and conversation and when you
say conversation failed what's the just
the two people walked out towards each
other
yeah or don't want to don't want to
listen right there's the impasse where
these two people probably are not either
going to be able to talk about this
thing or they just probably shouldn't be
in the meeting together or to learn and
to agree on action and then to actually
have the motivation and knowledge to act
well
all right well welcome to the
conversation thanks for joining us we
don't really happen agenda so I was like
let's bring it back to the agenda which
there isn't one of nobody so so now I'm
sorry for interrupting you but Lee what
would you like to share about the metal
project and your vision for it yeah so I
was thinking I guess it might be good to
kind of go around and kind of do it I
and say how we think we as a community
could support each other and in our
projects and specifically if you have
any AIDS in your project which is funny
right now
you know I last couple meetings I like
having this resource open and I like
being able to help everyone with it with
their projects where I can with some
skills I might have for a limited amount
of time but I I haven't needed much so I
don't have any immediate needs I guess I
was just thinking through you know
before we were talking about having apps
to pen a store a list of projects so we
know what people working on and stuff
like that
do we want to resurrect any of those or
or are we all doing pretty good right
now I'm thinking that something I could
use and maybe really that's what our our
Saturday mastermind meeting is for mayor
should be in the hot seat where I just
need to talk through some challenges I'm
having with finding how to use reason
score because every topic I try and
tackle is too complex to tackle with my
resources and I need kind of a good
sample project that's small enough to
tackle but interesting enough that I
won't be you know trying to dig my eyes
out could you could you just write
reasons yeah and it fits kind of in what
yours some of some of what you're saying
so you might find it interesting so it's
a it's a tool to help people map out
their discussions and applies this it
applies a score so
people can explore the reasons why they
think they should or should not do that
either as an individual or as a group
and I'd probably have to spend a lot of
time to get Oh detailed into it but in
general it is a process for people to
explore the reasons behind why they
think as a group we should do something
or not do something
it's a formalized process so it doesn't
do some of the other stuff that you are
looking for where you know helping
people I mean in a way it helps people
feel heard because they can get their
reasons in but it is very much kind of
fact-based as opposed to this is how I'm
feeling so it only covers like a half of
that but yeah it's a formalized process
to figure out to get people that are
disagreeing on either a fact or a path
of action to come to agreement based on
evidence yeah so yeah just an example on
that on my project I was gonna do some
stuff on nutrition and oh that's too big
for this one nutritional thing about a
way of eating whether it's healthy or
not in that and so I did just one part
of it and then I found that has a
hundred studies that would cost $50 to
get access to so that's $500 plus it's
learning and I read one on studies and
I'm like okay I kind of understand
p-values and stuff but the way they're
describing it doesn't make sense so now
I need a scientist to explain this to me
okay it's just a lot of work are you are
you in communication with other people
who have been working on adjacent topics
like are there people who are maybe
experts are studying the system of peer
review or something like that to
understand how how these larger systems
of sense-making within the scientific
communities work well I'm working with
like six other people and a group called
the canal
bait lab and the couple of them are
building their own projects in debate
mapping instance making but that's
different than the groups that are
working on peer-reviewed and kind of
group research I can't remember what
it's called literature reviews and stuff
like that because part of part of these
argument process will be linking to
scientific studies and and part of that
requires being literate and being able
to articulate not just the conclusions
but what though the statistics mean how
to interpret it how to interpret
potential issues with the experimental
design and and stuff like that as part
of the discussion how do you know how do
you get access to people who have the
knowledge to be able to explain and
interpret because they doesn't be
reliable as a person who's not biased in
what they will say about it
yeah the some topics will lend
themselves to that although this process
isn't just has to do with science so
there will be some topics that don't
even have studies in them at all so yeah
I could yeah I yeah I don't I don't
think I have a reason for someone else
to spend a lot of time on my project if
they have that skill set so I haven't
reached out to anyone Miller why would I
I mean I know a couple people that are
know of people that that looked at these
kind of umbrella and studies and did
some analysis on them so I could speak
to them but I haven't decided whether
it's really worth their time to reach
out to him yeah that is something where
your project in mind overlap so that
might be something that like if we start
to talk to scientists and stuff like
that way I'd be able to do that together
so it's sort of a group like hey is that
scenario where
we very much overlap and talking to
scientists trying to figure out like how
do we quantify the scientific review
process yeah
yeah it was really interesting to see us
doing this one study that took 15 random
of the controlled trial so they took all
the information and estimated I'm halls
to be there great if they degraded him
on the evidence and their potential
biasness and stuff like that so they had
a very specific process which i think
that could be generalized to our reason
score process but that the conclusion
from that study did not meet with my
biases so I was trying to discredit it
of course confirmation bias fully
enforce so yeah that's that's the thing
I'm struggling with right now but I've
quite figured out how I want some help
that so what could happen kind of in a
hot seat mastermind meeting would be I
would just kind of go through the
scenario with people and see what other
people kind of think about it
in detail I don't want to do that here
well yeah so one of the options is like
Billy like you said I reach out to some
people that do these literature reviews
and meta-analysis and and see if they
would help me struggle through this but
yeah the other option is just to find a
topic that doesn't have to do with
scientific studies one thing you
mentioned was you're reluctant to reach
out to people and ask for help because I
you don't want to waste their time and
I've just been thinking about um how we
figure out ideas of of how we make sure
that people are actually interacting
with each other and not afraid of having
interactions and finding mentorship and
providing mentorship to each other as a
resource
to enhance everyone's sense making his
and and I see these kinds of likes
discussions as as part of that but I am
interested in understanding it more
broadly as well yeah I think I mean
afraid maybe too strong of a word I I
want to be cautious that I'm making wise
use of resources so that's the only
thing is that if I have some people come
to me that ask me questions that they
haven't even done an internet search for
and I'd prefer not to do that to other
people because I think sometimes I think
sometimes we are worried that someone
else might feel like art we would be
wasting their time but we don't have a
way of actually knowing how what they
might actually be interested in as
people in engaging with them and if
their weather is as a project idea
finding some kind of project to make it
easier for people to communicate about
what they're willing to spend their time
on in helping others so that people
aren't afraid of reaching out to to
people who are maybe strangers or or
they don't know how busy they are
especially in a world where we aren't
physically walking around and seeing and
going to people's offices and seeing
whether it looks like they're really
busy right now
based on what they're doing but we are
just guessing about whether it's spam or
not doesn't love an email and things
like that
I think building on that reached out in
the game be space to ask like four or I
guess possibly even in game be projects
to ask who's a scientist and who might
be going to do that as Billy mentioned
if somebody's interested in sense-making
in that which seems likely that people
in the game beast basically some of them
might be see if there's that overlap a
little bit of I mean I've asked people
to see if they I guess not since on this
last issue and the reason is I haven't
quite figured out how to phrase the
question right I don't know how I need
help I just when I look at it I don't
want to do this work which you know I'm
not getting paid for this so right but
if I do it it'll never you know the
stuff I built will just disappear same
issue comes up a lot for the meta right
they're like no matter what your project
is you want to ask a blank write like
ask a scientist not even one scientist
you want to have a panel of scientists
you want have a panel that I don't know
if it's possible to have a simple plug
in the people can like add they're like
I'm like I'm not I'm BD what is the
LinkedIn right where you add like your
resume but more like hey I'm a scientist
I would not be willing to sit and be an
expert scientists but I'm willing to sit
on a scientific panel where I felt like
I had a sa right and so to be able to
send it out to all the scientists to say
hey I want to have a session at this
time who's willing to come and it not be
an inconvenience to them I know as
entrepreneurs people in charge of
projects we're ok kind of wasting our
own time on our project right you try
something it doesn't work you try
something new it doesn't work there's a
certain amount where we're not willing
to pay for that but if we did pay for it
would kind of be willing to let someone
else do it but we're asking people who
fall into your time and we're like wait
we don't want to go the wrong route and
yet it's the same as the entrepreneur
right it's still helping your thing if
there is no wasted if specially if it
comes from I just want to acknowledge as
well that Steve is watching because we
can't actually comment back and he said
something about that base project is
aware of his own bias and practices
scientific humility for reasons core
project no
yeah any likes that you're doing to
mentor chef Billy yeah I I can read that
I some other people haven't really been
talking much and maybe we could give
them an opportunity if they want our I'm
fine just not talking because I have
like lots of math on my mind and I'm
happy to just listen at this point well
okay so what I mean what you are talking
about is like creating something where
you just ask for someone with a certain
kind of background or competency to to
talk to you about things and and it
reminded me of something I that was like
it was like a suicide hotline type of
thing grief counseling like counts
volunteer counselling type of thing so
people try to just learn something and
then they can volunteer and talk and I
guess people just people who are looking
for someone to talk to
click themselves out maybe they give a
bit of information about themselves and
then volunteers
the person I talked to said it was very
fulfilling to them to to do this
volunteering and help people so I think
it's it's a very win-win type of thing
people want to feel they're being
helpful to others and so looking at how
those systems work might help in
designing systems that can be applied to
kind of parallel applications like
looking for people who are knowledgeable
about science and stuff like that and
you could you could have create more and
more of these kinds of of tools and
all right brah come to come this
together there's a there's a life's
library or you can rent people like
books for an hour I'm trying to think of
what the name of that project is but
that's kind of similar and then it also
reminds me of help a reporter out I
don't know if people seen that it's a
helper report out it's different but you
can post a story idea or reporters can
say hey I'm looking for a scientist in
this area those are kind of similar I
just want the repository of the people
to exist so weak so I can be in it and
also ask ask is it's like hey I mean I
just have this I don't know
world-changing icebucketchallenge type
thing and I'm like no matter how much
energy I put into something those
crickets so I'm literally willing to put
no energy into the pre part but if I
knew how to start an ice bucket
challenge if I knew how to actually tag
other people and like holds your own
solution raising on racism on food I
don't even care what the campaign is
literally anything and send it out into
the world and there's no the point of
that I don't know just that it's it's a
no point was another another thing that
I've seen is lunch club which i think is
like an invite thing but it's kind of
focused on meeting people with similar
interests and within your city to like
have lunch together in it so it's it's
all online now but they match you up
with a person it's kind of like I guess
like an online dating thing except it's
like matchmaking for people with
interesting similar project ideas and I
think it mostly has like software people
but it's it it kind of tries to be a
thing where people can find people to
potentially be like a co-founder of
start up with there's something like
that lunch club AI so that's another
inspiration potentially there's in-game
be but he was like look at this cool
thing but when you clicked on it you had
to be invited to join like so you have
someone who's doing in the lunch club
too it looked kinda like when Pinterest
first started which which he didn't post
but he didn't post that the invitation
it was just like look at this cool thing
you can't participate in which I don't
think he meant to I don't think he
didn't know you needed to be invited I
was like I don't think you can sign up
now I just went there and there's a spot
through email address than a button that
says sign up but I'm not sure I think
you can ask some of these things you can
request an invite or something maybe
maybe it's the more we encounter
literally any idea the more I'm like we
need a database of just like someone
like this thing and it's like that
already exists 17 times here go look at
all of them if you want to create
something new and different awesome but
like see the holes and see what's been
done in the past and to see that is we
need examples to think about data
structures that allow searchable
searchability of ideas and what what
would it look like to sew it so like
what what types of tags would you want
to have within your system and how do
you get people to find things and tag
them within the system and how do you
make your thing is a searchable database
of projects and and and tagged with
features that are like that are kind of
relevant that can't just be like
automatically figured out
and can't just be figured out just by
searching the text of their website or
something like that and also reputation
systems that give people an idea of what
other people think about how well done
and well implemented the the project
idea is and and maybe who has been who's
been contributing to it and valuable to
contributions like that who are your the
people who and and how and how and
guidance on on how to contribute or
Forker or find people to help you
understand how to fork and modify a
project those are all things that would
be good I I don't think I I still have
to learn a lot of program I mean before
I can implement any of the those types
of ideas though
yeah I'm trying to think I mean there
yeah I guess some of the problems is
finding the projects at their early
stage like if you know if you're looking
for businesses that are doing similar
things and there's an kaptara and
angellist
and producthunt to see what's already
kind of out there and also there are
several websites caught under the name
of alternative to that kind of rank
here's send our products to what you're
using that might be alternatives but
that all kind of falls apart when it's
kind of our projects which are not quite
as profit or business focused yeah how
how do you and and when you're a person
who is trying to do systems thinking and
stuff like that rather than just being
someone technical doing technical stuff
how do you market yourself as someone
who can help people who are building
social technologies to to improve their
social technologies and and and how do
you like show value it's not like a
thing that there's really a standardized
system where you can test people on how
how competent they are at that kind of
thing you and and being in the in the
game be space like you learn a lot of
things but it's not something you get
like a degree for there's no there's no
there's nothing to signal your your
usefulness in in contributing to
projects that may
needs people who have that kind of
background and and they're they're kind
of needs to be some amount of marketing
as an interaction with the people who
are doing major things to get them to
realize that some of these more
systems-thinking
perspectives can be very useful to them
useful to someone running a project like
like if you're on AngelList
how it's it's good at um you can call
yourself late you can say what kind of
technical programming languages stuff
you can do but there's not really a
category for how you describe your focus
in terms of thinking about social
technologies and secular technologies
and systems and now you specialize in
terms of your study of that kind of
stuff it's it's kind of tech oriented so
yeah yeah systems thinking isn't broadly
recognized yet as a category of skill
set what was the angel one called
I looked up angel dust and of course
that angel angel list I was like this
are never gonna get me there I was like
why would you name it angel dust that's
who's angel list thank you I think it's
angel list Co yeah is the actual name so
that's for startups mostly mm-hmm
for angel it's kind of a centralized
angel investor yeah platform
something about when Billy was talking
about like marketing because it's like
as the project right we all have issues
of marketing that the customer the user
has we have we saw the problem they
don't know they had and what Billy's
cocking is almost the opposite of that
that like the individual solves a
problem for the collective for whether
it's a corporation or a project or
whatever it is solves a problem for them
right they can do systems-thinking but
the project doesn't even know they need
that right they don't even know they
need the systems thinking and there's
something in I don't know in that like
the marketing yes almost like the
helping projects understand what they
don't know they don't know yeah no
people understand what they don't know
they don't know hey I notice you're very
technical in this have you thought about
bringing on a marketing person have you
thought about this like and then having
a network up here's 10 people you could
talk to and you know do you want to post
marketing do you feel you have a good
enough grasp like is there something
else that you think you need help with
[Music]
your audios cutting up yeah there's a
there's a need to kind of label and
describe people's job title that is kind
of reductionistic of a wide range of
things to just a few words right so it's
more like identifying a skill sets
instead of just I'm a developer well
great that narrows it down
I very much struggle with like resume
bit like do like would I play being part
of a community that that looks at social
problems in an integral perspective on a
resume is the only good thing
like it's there there are there are
difficulties in figuring out how to how
to that no what did value and how to
find what you need that is I am the new
leadership game be leadership group that
got created this last week and when I
joined there's questions you have to
answer and one of them is what
leadership roles have you had I was like
well I haven't like I mean I could pick
things out and be like look I was camp
counselor here are things that but it's
like I have actually avoided leadership
like the plague and avoided having
someone in leadership over me or being
in leadership over other people that
does not belong on a resume but it
actually gives me a very unique
perspective in leadership someone you
actually really want in the conversation
if you're talking about leadership I
don't know if you want me to leave no
believe me but to be part of that
conversation and it's the very like
medium to kind of I even put in there
I'm like nothing I could put on a resume
but I don't like to have leadership over
or under me and that is is a unique gift
and those it's like if it can be put on
a resume it's not uniquely yours and
it's not given how do you do it in the
world
and how do i yeah I think of leadership
less as being about having power or
authority as much as it is about leading
others and and taking taking
responsibility to to provide a vision
and to provide concrete steps to of
others and and helping keep and manage
communities as well
yeah and there is a very like
stewardship is what I would look at is
Pro II like game be leadership but there
just like the word and all of it my
point was like all of my bias all of
that stuff is important stuff to be out
that conversation and yet I might be the
last person they'd invite because
they're looking for the resume to say
right oh I was in as a person that was
in the game v-space if I kicked out who
posted the thing about boss versus he
didn't get kicked up for this
but boss versus leader and he's like put
on the buff like I'm the leader so
follow me it's like that's not
leadership
that really isn't you can't you aren't
assigned people to follow you and at the
same time there's like be in the unique
position of not wanting to be over
anyone or under anyone actually helps me
create non hierarchical structures and
now that I've matured enough I can I can
see that my auntie hierarchical is not
helpful but my profile up is and tend to
be part of of that and all of the
diversity that goes into leadership my
own bias is important to be in that
conversation as long as economic and
under set yeah I think I think there's
been if you know about integral
perspective I was listening to I forget
the name of the guy but the he was
talking about kind of how the green kind
of the the leftist type of thing has
become kind of regressive because it's
kind of been overly zealous about
hierarchies and and it's mistaken kind
of hierarchies of oppression for
hierarchies that are kind of positive
systems that are about organizing
thought and making it easier for people
to think and and order their
understanding of the world with in
layers and
and and and they oppose these these
structures which eat which are which are
these kind of hierarchies of sense
making that so they just they destroy
structures that are that are very useful
and positive because they just conflate
them with with hierarchies that are kind
of negative and so that's kind of like
the the problems of being overly anti
higher internal perspectives and as the
name suggests it's the stuff to do with
the integral theory right yeah okay just
making sure
so I guess then is that Simon dealt with
anything integral for years but is that
sort of like a pre trans thing with uh
with hierarchy like we have pre
hierarchy in the MIS of figuring it out
and we're talking about going trans
hierarchy like your audios hierarchies
are just like everywhere I mean the idea
is that you have to is that a higher he
is like a path and being higher in the
hierarchy means you've gone further
along the path and if you have gone
further along the path then by
definition then you kind of have a
relation that's more of a teacher kind
of role although you can see there still
thinks you can learn from anybody but
like like a hierarchy emerges from any
kind of system of teaching of people
where
you're you you described how far along
it's kind of linear in the traditional
sense of things like like kungfu belts
or something they kind of just give you
marriages or title based on how far
you've progressed in in your studies but
I think there is something really
meaningful and useful there but they
don't think it gives you authority to
control another person but it's still
the having a system that lets people
know that someone based on how high up
the hierarchy is it it just includes
within it inherently that they have
travelled all the levels that are below
that and I mean and hierarchies under
capitalism the people who are at the top
have not necessarily come from all the
levels below they don't have that
knowledge there and they don't have
investment and that's kind of more and
it's kind of more about control and
power but but I think it's a positive
hierarchy when you have kind of it's
like atoms molecules cells organisms
society is civilizations all of those
things counties hierarchies yeah these
or something
although Chrissie's sorry come on oh
yeah well hierarchies I sort of think of
them as being like either awarded or
earned so if there's like a No
Warda hierarchy you could think like
kings or just cuz you're the king
doesn't mean you're actually better at
anything it just means your king
that's all me yeah exact like it's some
like maybe your family earned it or
maybe yeah it was just like they did you
go out of a hat but whatever this is not
saying you're better at something but
then an urn hierarchy is like okay if
we're talking about who's you know the
best developer right or who's the best
at marketer who's the best at this if
somebody's are doing it for twenty five
years and every question you can to them
you have an answer you're like all right
they're probably near the top of the
Earned hierarchy that somebody who's
brand new just coming into it most
likely won't be as good I just skill
wise so if I'm trying to do like you
know if I'm Facebook if I'm like a
world-class sort of software company
trying to solve those problems my goal
is to get people at the top and in game
a pay them accordingly and then everyone
else has to sort of fight over where
they are in the hierarchy and how much
they're willing to pay versus that
person skill set and so I think from
what you were talking about sort of say
like good hi he's in bad hierarchies in
my mind the award the hierarchy is bad
as it doesn't mean anything
and the earned is it can be bad if it
it's sort of - I think that's one of the
problems with modern capitalism is the
people at the top of that they did have
a skill set they were usually good at
marketing or branding or positioning
themselves the problem being that now
that hierarchy is sort of the number one
one in the world and if you're at the
top of that you're doing well if you're
at the bottom you're probably starving
and so that's where it's like maybe if
you put too much emphasis on the
hierarchy that can be bad but it's not
necessarily a bad thing that there's
skill based hierarchy there's difference
between imposed hierarchies as in based
in elsi violence it's the most I think
and not well when there's hierarchy
because someone is better at making and
is able to
you know show it so others can see that
the others sense making us better and
then and so they follow it's a greeting
by example and this is very different
from like being in a place where you
have to take you have to take someone
else's viewpoint all nice making because
otherwise there will be consequences
yeah yes I think a leader is a person
who lots of people have chosen to follow
rather than someone who orders others
around and for me when I look at the
positivity of hierarchies that I may be
Aunty and pushed away versus what I that
the difference for me is not whether
it's given or earned it's whether I've
chosen to be in that power dynamic so in
a doctor relationship I don't have any
option than to be the patient's I can't
be the doctor but I have autonomy over
my own body so when there'll be expert
on medicine and then I have to listen to
them on my body that is hierarchy over
me that I don't like whereas if they
present me with their expertise and then
I get to make the decision that's not
hierarchy over me but I'm still dealing
with their earned expertise right I'm
still honoring that and the difference
is I get to choose right if it's on my
body I get to choose if I'm part of the
group of workers whatever it is and we
we elect someone or be just someone
naturally is the leader well if I get to
choose whether or not I'm there awesome
otherwise no and that is is again I'm
not saying it's bad or good but like aid
aid riyals difference and what he said
was good or bad and my difference just
means that we would be in conflict on if
we're trying to put those things into
the world right I'm trying to maximize
for choice and he'd be trying to
maximize for expertise or you know what
that would be and that would be the
conflict even though we don't have
conflict in some hierarchies can be good
and some hierarchies aren't right and
knowing like when to zoom out and see
the elephant is what I do like his
wording I've imposed and natural yes
and there's also internal and external
internal been I want to follow someone
or I want to trust someone who I think
has better knowledge about for example a
doctor because of all the medical
knowledge they have they suppose so I
choose to follow or listen to as opposed
to someone tells me that yeah I have to
listen because of something I see so
that sounds kind of like a third option
so there's internal imposed and natural
yeah extinct imposed or natural can be a
internal right
I wouldn't think because it's all just
you it's well it could be I mean imposed
because of internal conflict I have a
part of me sorry thanks boy and some
other part of me wants something
different so I have internal conflict
which then results in part of me
imposing certain path to follow
yeah but the simple thing is yeah
internal is is the not sure oh it's
different dimensions actually because
natural is also as the external part of
interacting with sorry that we as we
recognize as being external and better
and worth following or listening to and
yeah ok this is a good conversation
we've no way touched on the meta project
no this is so this week wasn't sorry we
did because this connect it is connected
because
the question and as the great problem
was formulated by Jordan Hall was how to
I'm sorry that's slightly different but
how to create and how to support natural
hierarchies as opposed to creating
external or imposed hierarchies around
so the way I see it is about how to make
people cooperate voluntarily right yeah
after let those natural hierarchies
establish and not try to you know like
say I'm the boss I'm this I'm that just
think as you're saying let it happen
naturally and let it sort of figure out
where people sit in the various
hierarchies like for me while I was in
the garden this last week there was
something about Anna dealing with the
leadership for free stuff and getting B
and all of that is what we we don't need
top-down monoculture gardening to feed
the world or to do any of this or
leadership we need permaculture we need
to allow the prosign if you know what
permaculture is but it's basically
growing plants in a way where they it
uses this little labor human labor as
possible because it's helping itself do
the weeding like the weeds just start
growing as much and pests aren't
happening as much and there's enough
yield because of how it's growing
together and you can't argue that you
know maybe you know I can't come in and
impose on tomatoes that they're not
acting like beans or beans that they're
not acting like tomatoes and yet there
is there's probably as a hierarchy to it
right some get Sun and some get shade
and some get all of this different stuff
and it's it's the system that works and
when you try to condemn you try to
top-down Authority it it breaks down and
like there's a way to create protocol
and the conditions that naturally and it
doesn't matter if you're like me and
don't like leadership it just now sure
it's like right that's me that's cool we
just won't lead you in that way I hope
can pick where that is it does actually
leave together
anyway this
sorry looks like Billy is continuing the
conversation in chat that's right yeah
either I mean he's mentioning that you
have to have a leadership wouldn't
disagreement exists or you need to have
a process because not all not all
disagreements are resolved by a person
but sometimes by process but yeah yeah
and I'm more into the process alright
that was up for like half a second you
pause yeah but leaders a much simpler
solution and more common yeah I think
that'll be one of the separations
between the individual projects and the
meta project together tech is it's like
kind of the structure is we each still
are the leader the owner whatever you
want to call up for our respective
projects and then four together attack
to be able to organize that we've kind
of understood no one person can be in
charge of it because it's a bunch of the
people who want to be in charge of their
own project and self ownership but then
still somehow figure out how to move
together as a community with both of
those happening in unison and if we
don't have any powerful needs then we
can keep the together tack another
project to just be kind of fulfilling
our individual project needs and how to
work together and stuff I think it would
be helpful to have that kind of tool
where people could find projects and be
a part of them and that may help us some
but I don't know that's a strong enough
need so we did conflict resolution as
children Adriel for three of us though
so you got the last piece if you cut the
cake you better cut it fairly I actually
think that that would be great
politicians yeah Richard one other
picture in my mind about the metal rod
project because at some point I
visualized all the different projects as
trying to paint a canvas in a certain
pattern
and then next thought was okay so the as
itself is like canvas of quite big and
there are places where there is
concentration of projects try to paint
on the same piece on the same like space
and no spaces where they are still blank
because no one cares about them or no
long thought about that they are even
there so meta project would be like
uncovering this just seen this big
picture and whether there is 20 projects
in one place and how to solve potential
to spread the painting process into into
pieces so they don't step on each
other's toes and then identifying the
blank spaces where any project would be
useful to create and take care of this
particular piece off of the campus
something like this like that analogy
yes I know there's some powerful stuff
happening internally around process
raising and because it's chaotic that
we're getting together and figuring it
out from the bottom up and Raymond
Raymond and I have different visions and
we're both really into working together
and creating something but we have very
different so it's like it keeps having
to come together and work through that
tension which is making it more powerful
this morning I did
I truly got the difference between
antifragility and and to you know yes
fragile resilience and Auntie fragile
that of course if you get knocked over
and get back up again that's resilient
but if you get back up and get stronger
every time that's auntie fragile and
that is actually what is being created
by not needing there to be leadership
there might eventually need to be
leadership right but like right now it's
like no we need to play in the tension
of there not being leadership of you get
to be on the same level having the same
version and then how do we how do we
work from here extort of try to bring
10,000 people together now the
conversations if we can't agree with the
two of us right how do we
how do we create something for here and
it's allowing to play in that chaos it
is something is coming out of some
permaculture or figuring out the
permaculture but we're just two little
sprouts awesome well it sounds like
we're coming to the end mm-hmm a couple
more men say you won't have any closing
thoughts I'll just remind people that
tomorrow morning
we're holding what we kind of a little
bit did today which is a project which
is the roundtables everyone comes and
brings their their project if they have
one they don't need to have one as they
can explain that give their elevator
pitch and then say what they what it is
that they would like help from from the
group we're doing that tomorrow at 9:00
a.m. is it standard time PDD whatever
that'sthat's fun I have a closing
thought actually talking about gardens
and permaculture I I'm not sure I didn't
study pond culture enough but there is a
role for pests and bugs and like the
nasty bugs we see in this picture right
and as I thought about it because of the
recent like they me group discussions
resulting in people being kicked out um
yeah I have ambiguous feelings about
there being too many I don't want to use
the word pests but people with very
different appeals and whether it it
helps with creating anti fragile thing
where because we in confrontation we've
extreme or different opinions and
beliefs
it makes the group stronger because it
helps
clarifying documents we have and why we
have them exactly and why they but they
are better as opposed so just didn't
read of the opinions that we don't like
yes I thought yeah yeah yeah I agree
yeah there's the limiting factor is some
people just want to cause disruption and
like I think it's it's a mix of how that
person was saying it not just what they
were saying like it's both it's though
is the what they're saying was troubling
but it was also the kind of combative
like if you don't agree with me you're
just stupid and that's just never gonna
be a good way to handle anything and so
that was I think it's and I'm a bit left
to some kind of ambivalent where like
it's kind of good and kind of bad the
end outcome with a lot you know a lot of
people who are kicked out I think is
probably the the correct thing in the
long term but I would have rather had
the interim step of having the
conversation around okay so what rules
do we need in place so that we can say
here's the rules that you you know broke
even though they weren't rules before so
here's the new rules that came out of
that going forward
be aware instead of this weird you broke
a rule that wasn't there so we're gonna
kick you out which is that part makes me
uncomfortable because then it's that can
happen to anyone
yeah which to me is the differencing
hierarchy down rules that that are like
these are the rules and then bureaucracy
needs to take place versus something
that's more alive like permaculture
because the person I think you're
talking about the white supremacist a
guy actually practiced I'll make a rule
better than the rest of us hold in a lot
of ways and so there was like a
technical not breaking of the rules with
the technical breaking of the rules and
it's like okay so now we need a new rule
that applies to this and not to that and
there is kind of a like no we don't need
a new rule just no expert like no if you
think that white people are superior
right not different superior there's no
space for that here we're not giving
that time and energy and it's but then
there comes all the shame and you're
wrong for believing it which then adds
all the other stuff on top of it but
there was something about that he showed
up and actually could skillfully kind of
say these things without losing his
sovereign
like a lot of people do in that space
and so it's like well technically you're
doing this and not that and then other
people were like technically on like
losing their sovereignty but not in that
conversation other conversations about
about race and other and other things
and showy and you know demeaning and
becoming strong men and are doing this
Drummond attack and that kind of stuff
as well there's anyway pasty pasty our I
didn't mean to step on Matus Asst
closing thoughts because those are much
better than what I just said but we will
see you tomorrow morning for our
Roundtable goodbye Facebook